<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on 🔮 Merlin's Beard</title><link>https://john-pettigrew.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on 🔮 Merlin's Beard</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.136.5</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:56:38 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://john-pettigrew.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🙉 Wyoming 2 - speak up</title><link>https://john-pettigrew.github.io/posts/wyoming-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:56:38 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://john-pettigrew.github.io/posts/wyoming-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="last-time">Last time&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my previous post I discussed creating a client for the Wyoming Protocol called &lt;a href="https://github.com/john-pettigrew/wyoming-cli">wyoming-cli&lt;/a> that could request spoken audio to be generated from text. I decided to continue working on this project and add what I think is the next logical piece of functionality, ASR or automatic speech recognition. This means I should be able to provide either audio data from a microphone or from an audio file and have the speech transcribed. As a bonus since these servers are typically used for talking to smart assistants, getting a response doesn&amp;rsquo;t take very long.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🦬 Wyoming In Go</title><link>https://john-pettigrew.github.io/posts/wyoming/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 13:20:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://john-pettigrew.github.io/posts/wyoming/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-setup">The Setup&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I was working on a side project the other day and I needed to generate some spoken audio from generated text. This is called &amp;ldquo;Text to Speech&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;TTS&amp;rdquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s also &amp;ldquo;Speech to Text&amp;rdquo; or STT, and a few other acronyms to memorize for fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of Home Assistant and last year they had several updates for their &amp;ldquo;Year of the Voice&amp;rdquo;. These updates gave the project functionality like those home smart speakers that were super popular for a while. One benefit of having this in Home Assistant is privacy! All your requests to &amp;ldquo;turn off the kitchen light&amp;rdquo; will be safely stored away from prying eyes, on a server you trust.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>